

Jenade Moodley

Cloud Engineer



jenademoodley68+resume@gmail.com



Cape Town, Western Cape, ZA



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jenademoodley/



https://github.com/jenademoodley



ABOUT

Seasoned Cloud Engineer with experience in Cloud, System, and Software Engineering. Bachelor of Science Honours in Computer Science from university of Kwa-Zulu Natal. Skilled in Cloud Architecture, Linux System Engineering, Technical Support, Technical Training, and Containers. Based in South Africa, Cape Town



WORK EXPERIENCE

Cloud Support Engineer, Amazon Web Services

Dec 2017 - Present 2 years 7 months

Amazon Web Services (AWS) is the world's most comprehensive and broadly adopted cloud platform, offering over 175 fully featured services from data centers globally.

- Promoted from Graduate to Associate, and then to Engineer, within the space of 1.5 years
- Became a Quality Champion; Evaluate the quality and appropriateness of Support correspondences of engineers
- Pioneer for the AWS Premium Support Andon Program (PSAP) in Cape Town
- Member of ECS (Elastic Container Service) Support Operations
- Trained engineers globally on Docker, containerization, and ECS/Fargate

Student Tutor, University of Kwa-Zulu Natal

Jan 2017 - Nov 2017 ② 10 months

UKZN is one of three universities in South Africa and indeed in Africa rated amongst the top 500 universities of the world according to the Academic Rankings of World Universities (ARWU)

- Assisted in teaching of tutorials and practicals
- Graded assignments and practical assessments



Systems Engineering (master): Networking, Load Balancing, Web Applications, Nginx, Apache, MySQL.

Programming (intermediate): Java, Python, C++, PHP, JavaScript.

Linux (professional): RedHat, CentOS, Ubuntu, Kernel, Debugging, Troubleshooting.

Cloud Architecture (professional): AWS, Azure, GCP, VPC, CloudEndure, EC2, ECS, RDS, EFS, ElastiCache.



EDUCATION

Computer Science, **Bachelor of Science**, University of Kwa-Zulu Natal

Jan 2014 - Dec 2016

Computer Science

Mathematics

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science Honours, University of Kwa-Zulu Natal

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Summa Cum Laude

Computer Science (Advanced)



AWARDS

Linux+, CompTIA

Awarded on: Apr 2018

CompTIA Linux+ validates the competencies required of an early career system administrator supporting Linux systems.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, Amazon Web Services

Awarded on: Jun 2020

The AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate examination is intended for individuals who perform a solutions architect role and have one or more years of hands-on experience designing available, cost-efficient, fault-tolerant, and scalable distributed systems on AWS.

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate, Amazon Web Services

Awarded on: Jul 2020

The AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate examination is intended for systems administrators in a systems operations role with at least one year of experience in deployment, management, and operations on AWS.



PUBLICATIONS

Weather Characterization from Outdoor Scene Images, International Conference on Computer Vision and Graphics

Published on: Sep 19, 2018

Research paper presenting a variety of techniques to characterize outdoor scene images into their respective weather components; the sky condition (sunny or cloudy), the presence of rain, and the visibility.



INTERESTS

Gaming

Open World RPG

Hiking

Beautiful Scenery



Languages

English (Native speaker), **Afrikaans** (Limited working proficiency).